<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Writing | Code Snacks]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.kanaabe.com/blog/categories/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.kanaabe.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-15T19:11:24-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.kanaabe.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kana Abe]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code Every Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.kanaabe.com/blog/2015/01/15/code-every-day/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-15T17:41:37-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.kanaabe.com/blog/2015/01/15/code-every-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Starting 2015, I wanted to write code every day. This meant making at least one meaningful open-source commit each day. It was inspired by John Resig in <a href="http://ejohn.org/blog/write-code-every-day/">this post</a>. All was going well, I felt confident, and submitted good code.</p>

<p>And then I broke it on January 3.</p>

<p>Just 6 days in (I started December 28) and I couldn&rsquo;t keep up with my grand plan. Needless to say I was embarrassed and thought this would be impossible. Well, it is. I mean it&rsquo;s <em>possible</em> to write code every day for the rest of your life but in a realistic life-setting, mistakes happen, life happens. <strong>You can&rsquo;t expect to form a concrete habit in one shot</strong>.</p>

<p>Just keep swimming. All I can ask of myself is that the next time I break the streak, it better be longer than 6 days and it <em>better</em> be for a good reason. My current streak is 12 days and I&rsquo;m feeling pretty happy. In fact, I&rsquo;m really proud of all the work that&rsquo;s been done in just 12 days.</p>

<p>I finished a game, I updated the look and feel of this blog, fixed a bunch of bugs that bothered me, started re-designing my boyfriend&rsquo;s portfolio site, and today I dug up my legacy portfolio site and started cleaning. <em>Oh, cleaning.</em> What a wonderful feeling to see terribly designed code and start cleaning.</p>

<p>One fear that&rsquo;s been coming up a lot is: what&rsquo;s going to happen when I start a new job? Ideally I&rsquo;ll be writing code every day at my job, but what about the weekends? Will I be too tired? What if my job doesn&rsquo;t have open-sourced projects? Look, I didn&rsquo;t sign a contract to do this - I&rsquo;m doing this to be a better coder. Right now, this is the best way I can think of to do that. <strong>It doesn&rsquo;t have to be forever, but it should be consistent for as long as it matters</strong>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been trying at this habit for about a month now and it&rsquo;s been a very therapeutic experience. I get excited to open up my computer and pick up where I left things, still fresh. I don&rsquo;t plan on stopping when I start a new job because I&rsquo;m feeling a lot of the positive side-effects that John Resig talks about in his post. I can&rsquo;t wait to hit that 1 year streak. It will happen, and it will happen naturally!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
